Guide to the Brooklyn Heights Association Records BCMS.0035
Brooklyn Collection
Brooklyn Heights Association Records
1917-1990
Brooklyn Collection
Brooklyn Heights Association (New York, N.Y.).
BCMS.0035
47.0 Cubic feet in 18 record cartons, 27 document boxes, 1 oversize flat box
Inactive records of the Brooklyn Heights Association consisting of news clippings, correspondence, financial records, lawsuits, reports, and memorabilia.
Provenance
Donated by the Brooklyn Heights Association, 2007.
Access
Collection is located in the Brooklyn Collection at the Central Branch at Grand Army Plaza. The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.
Arrangement
The collection is maintained in the original order established by the Brooklyn Heights Association. Most files are arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection is dated 1950-1970 and focuses on the successful bid to make the neighborhood a historic landmark. It includes extensive correspondence with mayors, borough presidents, and agency heads. Records also cover such topics as air pollution, tree planting, noise pollution, Brooklyn Union Gas, and Burger King. Meeting minutes, reports, and documents from various lawsuits brought by the Brooklyn Heights Association also make up a large portion of the subject files.
Another significant portion of the subject files is the Brooklyn Heights Association Piers files, dating from 1986-1989. These files represent the successful attempt by the Association to set guidelines for the redevelopment of the docks and piers under and around the Brooklyn Promenade and the Brooklyn Bridge before the creation of the Brooklyn Bridge Park.
The Brooklyn Heights Association retained extensive records on the Civilian Observation Patrol or C.O.P. program. Documents include safety reports, patrol reports, correspondence, grant applications, patrol logs, reports, and surveys.
Two other areas of significance are the records of the Roebling Project and the financial records from 1924-1982. The Roebling project includes grant applications and fundraising efforts, artist submissions, renderings and correspondence. This project was the Association's attempt to honor Brooklyn Bridge architect John A. Roebling with a statue. The financial records include expenditures, revenue, and cash receipts. The financial records detail financial ties with members and organizations as well as salary payouts.
Historical Note
The Brooklyn Heights Association is a volunteer community organization focused on the neighborhood of Brooklyn Heights. Established in 1910, the Association is the oldest ongoing neighborhood association in the city. The board is governed by volunteers and primary activities focus on local issues such as development, parks, preservation of the neighborhood's historical character through advocacy and dissemination of information.
Related Materials
Brooklyn Archival Files: Brooklyn Heights Association, Folders 1-6
Brooklyn Heights Association Brooklyn Heights: yesterday, today, tomorrow. 1937.
Brooklyn Heights Association. The origins of New York's historic districting. 2000
Brooklyn Heights Association. Enjoying Brooklyn Heights: the Brooklyn Heights Association's self-guided neighborhood walking tour. 2010
Buckhurst, Fish, Hutton, Katz (Firm). The future of the piers: planning and design criteria for Brooklyn piers 1-6. The Firm. 1987.
Everdell, William R. Rowboats to rapid transit: a history of Brooklyn Heights. 1973
Schneider, Martin L. Battling for Brooklyn Heights: the fight for New York's first historic district. 2010
Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Historic districts--New York (State)--New York; Neighborhood Associations; Waterfronts
- Annual Reports, Including Presidents' Papers, 1923-1966 (Box 1)
- Air Pollution and Noise, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Air Pollution and Noise, 1977 (Box 1)
- Air Pollution Committee, 1960-1966 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1928 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1929 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1930 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1931 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1932 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1933 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1940 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1934 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1942 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1936 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1935 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1937 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1938 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1939 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1948 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1949 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1947 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1946 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1945 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1944 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1943 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Report of Committees, 1926-1927 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports - Cleanliness and Smoke Abatement, 1927-1965 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1941 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Programs, 1923-1958 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1960 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1961 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Community Report – Civic Improvement, 1958 (Box 1)
- Annual Report Research, 1966 (Box 1)
- Annual Report, 1966 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Reports - Cleanliness, 1966 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Report of Committees, 1926 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports – Cleanliness and Smoke Abatement, 1927 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Programs, 1923-1959 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Design Advisory Council, 1963-1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports - Education, 1959 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Report – Historical Preservation, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports – Housing Violations, 1955 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Reports - Membership, 1956 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Reports - Montague Street Improvement, 1962 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1965 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1964 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1963 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1962 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Report - Noise Police and Traffic, 1959-1966 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Reports - Planting, 1962 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Reports - Police, 1962 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Invitations, Programs, Questions, 1923-1958 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Programs – Theatrical Productions (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports – Publicity, 1956 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports – Recreation, 1956 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports – Smoke, 1962 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports - Traffic, 1926 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Treasurers Reports, 1954 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports - Trees, 1968 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Report – Urban Renewal, 1960 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Report – Zoning, 1927 (Box 1)
- Atlantic Avenue Pier, 1959 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting – Ideas, 1960 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Report - Cleanliness, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Report - Design Advisory Council, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Report - Education, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Report - Design Advisory Council, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Report - Education, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Report -Historic Preservation, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee - Housing Violations and Zoning, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee - Membership, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee - Planting and Trees, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee - Police, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1969 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1968 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, Robert Moses Spoke, 1967 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Committee Reports Citation – Property Improvement, 1953 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1972 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1975 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1974 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1973 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1971 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1970 (Box 1)
- Address of City Officials and Other Government Officials Administration, 1977 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Minutes, 1953-1970 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Minutes, 1971-1980 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Information, circa 1960-1979 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Memo, 1959 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1959 (Box 1)
- Annual Committee Reports - Nominating Committee, 1955-1980 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting President's Speech, 1969-1979 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1980 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1981 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1979 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1978 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1977 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1976 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
- Annual Meeting Citations, circa 1966-1978 (Box 2)
- Annual Committee Report Air Pollution and Noise, 1967 (Box 2)
- Annual Committee Report - Publicity, 1967 (Box 2)
- Annual Committee Report - Recreation, 1967 (Box 2)
- Annual Committee Report - Research, 1967 (Box 2)
- Annual Committee Report - Street Lighting
- Annual Committee Report - Traffic, 1967 (Box 2)
- Annual Committee Report - Urban Renewal, 1967 (Box 2)
- Art Show (Box 2)
- Art Show Brooklyn Heights Artists Brooklyn Museum, 1969 (Box 2)
- Arcade St. George Hotel, 1976-1979 (Box 2)
- Assumption School, 1972 (Box 2)
- Auditing Report General Fund and Playground Fund, 1932-1953 (Box 2)
- Articles on Brooklyn Heights (Box 2)
- BHA Current, 1965 (Box 2)
- Bi-Centennial, 1976 (Box 2)
- Block Associations, circa 1970-1979 (Box 2)
- Block Associations, circa 1980-1989 (Box 2)
- Blocks 207 and 211, 1973 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1974 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1973 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1967 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
- Block 207, 1979-1982 (Box 2)
- Ziegelbaum Property Block 239, 1981 (Box 2)
- Blocks 207 and 211, 1964 (Box 3)
- Jane C. McConnell #1 Newspaper Clippings
- Brooklyn Heights Association Brochure, 1960 (Box 3)
- Ziegelbaum Property (Box 3)
- Board of Governors – Additions and Resignations, 1924-1972 (Box 3)
- Board of Governors – Additions and Resignations, 1973-1981 (Box 3)
- Board Members New – Comm List (Box 3)
- Board of Governors & Advisory Committee – Correspondence (Box 3)
- Board of Trade (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Bridge Walkway/ Bikeway (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Heights Etchings (by Joseph Penel who lived on Columbia Heights, reproductions), 1921-1926 (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Brownstone Conference, 1974 (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Rediscovery, 1979 (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Heights Community Council Financial Records, 1963 (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Organizations (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Vocational Rehabilitation Institute, 1978 (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Union Gas (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Queens Expressway, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Queens Expressway, circa 1940-1949 (Box 3)
- Burger King, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
- Burger King, 1976 (Box 3)
- Bulletins, October 1955-1959 (Box 3)
- Bulletins, 1960-1965 (Box 3)
- Bulletins, 1966-1972 (Box 3)
- By Laws Revisions, 1972 (Box 3)
- By Laws Revisions, 1959 (Box 3)
- By Laws Changes and Development, 1948-1960 (Box 3)
- By Laws, Proposed Revisions, Etc., 1910-1948 (Box 3)
- Christmas Tree Club Forms, 1958-1976 (Box 3)
- Church of the Assumption, pictures (Box 3)
- City Officials – Correspondence – Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Cleanliness, 1977 (Box 4)
- Catholic Charities (Box 4)
- Charities Contributions (Box 4)
- City Planning Commission (Box 4)
- City Services (Box 4)
- Civic Associations (Box 4)
- Commercial Membership Emblem (Box 4)
- Committee Chairmen Correspondence, 1975-1981 (Box 4)
- Committee Chairman Reports Annual, 1980 (Box 4)
- 222 Columbia Heights (Box 4)
- Cranberry Street Association (Box 4)
- Container Port (Box 4)
- Cranberry Street Association (Box 4)
- Community Boards (Box 4)
- Community Planning Board #2 [Block Grant Program] (Box 4)
- Community Planning Board #2 I (Box 4)
- Community Planning Board #2 II (Box 4)
- Community Planning Board #2 III (Box 4)
- Crime Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
- Crime Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
- Crime Committee, 1976 (Box 4)
- Downtown Brooklyn Development Committee (Box 4)
- Design Advisory Council, 1962-1967 (Box 4)
- Design Advisory Council, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
- Design Advisory Council, 1971 (Box 4)
- Education School Board Elections, March 1970 (Box 4)
- Esplanade Streets and Sidewalks, 1973 (Box 4)
- Esplanade Streets and Sidewalks, 1977 (Box 4)
- Esplanade Streets and Sidewalks Environment, 1977 (Box 4)
- Esplanade Brooklyn Heights, 1979 (Box 5)
- Esplanade, Streets, and Sidewalks Letters, June 1971-March 1972 (Box 5)
- Environment (Box 5)
- Filming in Brooklyn Heights, 1975-1979 (Box 5)
- Financial Records, 1922-1933 (Box 5)
- Finances BHA, 1975-1977 (Box 5)
- Fire Protection (Box 5)
- Fire Records 173-175 Hicks Street, 1968 (Box 5)
- Fire Department (Box 5)
- Fire House Closing, 1975 (Box 5)
- Fort Sterling Park (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry Renaissance Association (Box 5)
- Fort Greene Meat Market, 1968 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry Site, 1971-1973 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry, 1974 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry, 1975 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry I, 1976 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry II, 1976 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry, 1977 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry, 1979 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry, 1980 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry I, 1981 (Box 5)
- Fulton Ferry II, 1981 (Box 5)
- Empire Stores (Box 6)
- Fulton Street Mall, 1976 (Box 6)
- 336 and 374 Furman Street, 1981 (Box 6)
- Golden Jubilee Meetings and Programs, 1960 (Box 6)
- Golden Jubilee Year Correspondence I (Box 6)
- Golden Jubilee Year Correspondence II (Box 6)
- Golden Jubilee Chairman's File (Box 6)
- Gowanus Canal (Box 6)
- Hotels, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
- Hotels, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
- Historic District Council, 1972 (Box 6)
- Heights Hill Community Council, 1971 (Box 6)
- Historical Preservation Bard Law, 1959 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation - Tax Reform Act, 1976 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation, 1965 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation, 1962 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation, 1963-1964 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation National Landmark, 1965 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation I, 1970-1973 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation II, 1970-1973 (Box 6)
- Historic Preservation, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
- Historic Preservation, 1976 (Box 7)
- Historic Preservation, Preservation of Historic Districts (Box 7)
- Historical Record of Brooklyn Heights Compiled 1952 and brought up to date 1960 (Box 7)
- History of Brooklyn Heights Association, Ed Pinto Compilation (Box 7)
- Hotels – Brooklyn Heights, 1968-1973 (Box 7)
- History Brooklyn Heights Association – Past Accomplishments compiled in 1960 (Box 7)
- Homosexuality, 1972 (Box 7)
- Hotels Brooklyn Heights, 1974 (Box 7)
- Housing (Box 7)
- Hotels (Box 7)
- Housing Issues, 1981 (Box 7)
- Historic Preservation Walking Tour (Box 7)
- Historical Booklet on Heights, 1937 (Box 7)
- Historical Material Relating to Brooklyn Heights (Box 7)
- Jehovah's Witnesses (Box 7)
- Land Development Committee (Box 7)
- Land Use (Box 7)
- Law Committee (Box 7)
- Legislation, 1971 (Box 7)
- Legal Committee (Box 7)
- Lincoln Savings Bank – Brooklyn Heights Association Exhibit, 1971 (Box 7)
- Long Island College Hospital (Box 7)
- Low Memorial Child Care Center (Box 7)
- Obituary Resolutions (Box 7)
- Maps (Box 7)
- Maps and Diagrams (Box 7)
- Maps and Blueprints Detail (Box 7)
- Montague Street Improvement, 1968-1978 (Box 7)
- Montague Street Improvement, 1976 (Box 7)
- Montague Street Improvement, 1977-1978 (Box 7)
- National Maritime Historical Society (Box 7)
- News Clippings (Box 7)
- Office Lease (Box 7)
- Office Equipment (Box 7)
- Oil Delivery Trucks, 1970 (Box 7)
- Old Brooklyn Heights – Brooklyn Savings Bank (folder empty), 1927 (Box 7)
- Organization – BHA, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
- Our Lady of Lebanon Church (Box 8)
- Parking (Box 8)
- Permanent Records (Box 8)
- Play Areas (Box 8)
- Photographs, Remsen Street, Henry Street and Grace Court (Box 8)
- Police Committee, 1959 (Box 8)
- Police Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
- Police Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
- Prospect Park Celebration (Box 8)
- Police and Anti Noise Committee, 1957-1959 (Box 8)
- Public Improvements (Box 8)
- Publicity Committee Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 8)
- Post Office (Box 8)
- Press Conference, Slum Clearance – Cadman Plaza, June 1960 (Box 8)
- Promenade Lights, 1965 (Box 8)
- Publicity Committee, 1961 (Box 8)
- Palmieri (125 Montague) (Box 8)
- Pamphlets – What Every Landlord and Tenant Should Know (Box 8)
- Park Department Correspondence (Box 8)
- The Parks Council, 1970 (Box 8)
- Patrol Car, 1981 (Box 8)
- Peak's Factory, 1976 (Box 8)
- Pending Matters, 1975 (Box 8)
- People - BHA People (Box 8)
- Petty Cash Reports, 1960-1970 (Box 8)
- Petty Cash Reports, 1971-1981 (Box 8)
- Phoenix Organization (Box 8)
- Physical Plant (Box 8)
- Pierrepont Hotel (Box 8)
- Pierrepont Playground (Box 8)
- Perman Buildings (Box 8)
- Planning Book #2 (Part 1) (Box 8)
- Pkanning Book #2 (Part 2) (Box 8)
- Redistricting (Congressional) Clippings, 1982 (Box 8)
- Rowboats to Rapid Transit (Box 8)
- St. Ann's Church, 1980 (Box 8)
- St. George Hotel (Box 8)
- Streets - 360 Furman Street, 1981 (Box 8)
- 23 Schermerhorn (Box 8)
- 20 Schermerhorn (Box 8)
- Spencer Memorial Church I (Box 8)
- Spencer Memorial Church II (Box 8)
- Squibb Park, 1981 (Box 8)
- Street Lighting (Box 9)
- Street Lights (Box 9)
- Streets and Sidewalks, 1967 (Box 9)
- Subway Entrance Clark Street (Box 9)
- Subway Entrance Cranberry Street (Box 9)
- Subway Vibrations Joralemon Street, 1977 (Box 9)
- Subway Closings (Box 9)
- Tax Reform Act of 1976 (Box 9)
- Tax Exempt Status, 1980 (Box 9)
- Towers Hotel (Box 9)
- Traffic, 1967-1972 (Box 9)
- Traffic, 1973-1975 (Box 9)
- Traffic, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
- Transit Authority – Clark Street Elevators, 1961-1976 (Box 9)
- Transit Authority, 1971-1981 (Box 9)
- Treasurer's Correspondence, 1971-1980 (Box 9)
- Treasurers Reports, 1956-1966 (Box 9)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1953-1955 (Box 9)
- Tree Committee, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
- Tree Committee, 1967-1973 (Box 9)
- Tree Committee, 1974-1977 (Box 9)
- Tree Campaign Golden Jubilee, 1960 (Box 9)
- Tree Campaign, 1961 (Box 9)
- Trees Promenade (Box 9)
- Tree Planting Campaigns, 1924-1932 (Box 9)
- Trees and Flower Boxes, 1960-1962 (Box 9)
- Trees and Planting, 1965-1968 (Box 9)
- Trees and Planting, 1969-1972 (Box 9)
- Tree Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 9)
- Tree Orders, 1972 (Box 9)
- Tree Orders, 1968 (Box 9)
- Planting and Trees (Box 9)
- Trees – London Plane Project, 1981 (Box 9)
- Vest Pocket Park Clark Street, 1966 (Box 9)
- Vice Presidents, 1975 (Box 9)
- Vice President Administration (Box 9)
- Vice President Environment (Box 9)
- Vice President Land (Box 9)
- Vice President People (Box 9)
- Village Homeowners Association, 1972 (Box 9)
- Volunteers, 1971-1980 (Box 9)
- Walking Tour – BHA (Box 9)
- Watchman - Private, 1924 (Box 9)
- Waterfront Planning, 1974 (Box 9)
- Waterfront Study, 1979 (Box 9)
- Waterfront and Waterways, 1973 (Box 9)
- Waterfront (folder empty), 1972 (Box 9)
- Waterfront, 1971 (Box 9)
- Water Supply, Gas and Electricity, 1965 (Box 9)
- Welfare Hotels, 1971 (Box 9)
- Westway, 1977 (Box 10)
- Wildfire (Club), 1982 (Box 10)
- Willowtown Association, 1966 (Box 10)
- You and Your Community Board (Box 10)
- Youth Council, 1978-1980 (Box 10)
- Zoning Violations, 1964 (Box 10)
- Zoning Re Bohack Company, 1952 (Box 10)
- Zoning Change (Residential to Commercial) Clinton/Schermerhorn, 1931 (Box 10)
- Zoning - Clark Street, 1923-1941 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Jehovah's Witness Dormitory (Box 10)
- Zoning – Norwegian Club, 1936 (Box 10)
- Zoning – 9, 13, 15 College Place Alterations (Box 10)
- Zoning – Grace Court Alley, 1924 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Harrison Ballard and Allen report (Box 10)
- Zoning – Heights of Buildings, 1937-1939 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Hicks Street, 1931 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Liquor and Cabaret Licenses (Box 10)
- Zoning – Love Lane Garage, 1924-1929 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Love Lane Garage, 1936 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Important Cases, 1921-1952 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Monroe Place, 1952 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Miscellaneous (Box 10)
- Zoning – Movie Theatre (Montague & Henry), 1928 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Projecting Signs, 1933-1937 (Box 10)
- Zoning – 122 and 124 Remsen Street, Re-Zoning, 1921-1923 (Box 10)
- Zoning – 140 Remsen Street, 1925 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Remsen Street Re-Zoning, 1926 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Re-Zoning of Heights, 1957 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Re-Zoning Plan, 1959-1961 (Box 10)
- Zoning – St. George Parking Garage (Box 10)
- Zoning – Parking Garage, 1956 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Set Back Restrictions – Amended, 1928 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Waterfront Restrictions, 1932 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Waterfront Zone S, 1952-1959 (Box 10)
- Zoning – 140 Remsen Street - Photos, 1925-1927 (Box 10)
- Zoning – Womens' Court, 1929 (Box 10)
- Zoning - ReZoning – Schulman Report 1959 (Urban Renewal and Zoning Resolution of 1961) (Box 10)
- Zoning – Pierrepont Covenant – Real Estate Restrictions Imposed, 1870 (Box 10)
- Zoning, 1967-1975 (Box 10)
- Zoning, 1976 (Box 10)
- Zoning, 1977-1979 (Box 10)
- Zoning, 1980 (Box 10)
- Newsclippings Brooklyn Heights General, 1982 (Box 10)
- Statistical Portrait of Brooklyn Heights, 1965 (Box 10)
- History BHA – Larry Fields – Various Public Statements by BHA on itself, 1960-1965 (Box 10)
- Newsclippings – Promenade and Expressway (Box 10)
- Lenehan, Gary Steven (Burger King), 1975-1976 (Box 10)
- Child Safety Programs - Draft Report on SRO in Brooklyn Heights, 1974 (Box 10)
- Fast Food - Burger King (Box 11)
- Criminal Activity, 1979-1982 (Box 11)
- Brooklyn Heights Association Financial Statements, 1980-1982 (Box 11)
- Center for the Visual Environment – Ordinances (Box 11)
- Legal Papers Concerning the Brooklyn Queens Expressway (Box 11)
- City Planning Commission – Community Planning Handbook (Box 11)
- B.H.A. Monthly Receipts and Disbursements, 1975-1980 (Box 11)
- Zoning Variances (Box 11)
- BHA Questionnaires, 1973, 1975-1977 (Box 12)
- BHA Questionnaires (Box 12)
- Correspondence of Scott Hand (Box 12)
- Blood Program, 1966 (Box 12)
- Blood Bank, 1967 (Box 12)
- Board Membership Memo and Communications, 1962-1971 (Box 12)
- Board Membership Memo and Communications, 1972 (Box 12)
- Board Membership Memo and Communications, 1973-1975 (Box 12)
- Board Members and Executive Committee, 1952-1973 (Box 12)
- Board of Governors Attendance Sheets (Box 12)
- Booklet of Business Directory, 1936 (Box 12)
- Boerum Hill (Box 12)
- Brochure Draft, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
- Brochure Development Material, 1959 (Box 12)
- Brochure Draft, 1952 (Box 12)
- Brooklyn Bridge Plaza, 1929 (Box 12)
- Brooklyn Bridge Plaza, 1938-1941 (Box 12)
- Brochure Draft, 1952 (Box 12)
- Brooklyn Daily (Box 12)
- Brooklyn Heights Press (Box 12)
- Brooklyn Today, Inc. (Box 12)
- Brooklyn Progress Report Pamphlets (Box 12)
- Bulletin – Ideas (Box 12)
- Bulletin – Masthead Negative (Box 12)
- Citation Committee Reports, 1937-1951 (Box 12)
- Civic Improvement Committee, 1960-1966 (Box 12)
- Civic Improvement Committee, 1967 (Box 12)
- Cleanliness Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 12)
- Cleanliness Committee, 1959-1964 (Box 12)
- Cleanliness Committee, 1955-1959 (Box 12)
- Cleanliness Committee, 1923-1953 (Box 12)
- Cleanliness Campaign, 1949 (Box 12)
- Cleanliness Campaign, 1952 (Box 12)
- Cobble Hill Association, 1959-1975 (Box 12)
- Committees on Churches (Box 12)
- Committee Chairmen and V.P. Memos, 1960-1975 (Box 12)
- Committee Member List, 1923-1965 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Cleanliness, 1969-1961 (Box 12)
- Committee Minutes – Education & Recreation (Box 12)
- Committee of 100, 1939 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Education & Recreation, 1946-1962 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Housing, 1946-1959 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Housing Violations, 1960 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Membership, 1933-1969 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Miscellaneous, 1934-1960 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Noise, 1923-1959 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Publicity, 1943-1956 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Traffic, 1935-1961 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Trees, 1957-1960 (Box 12)
- Committee Reports – Interim Zoning, 1923-1961 (Box 12)